Michael J. Miller

Orlando, FL | (407)453-9385

michael.joseph.miller@proton.me | www.linkedin.com/in/mjmiller41

Professional Summary

In-depth knowledge and skills with various computing systems software and hardware, including Windows, Linux command line, and MS Excel/Word/PowerPoint. Top notch troubleshooting and problem-solving skills. Strong understanding of electrical and electronic fundamentals. Excellent verbal and written communication skills and customer service experience.

Education

A.S. Information Technology and Networking GPA 3.71	*In progress (Grad. Aug 2023)
 DeVry University, Orlando FL 	Orlando, FL
A.S. Small Vessel Operations	1997
Maine Maritime Academy	Castine, ME
Basic Electronics Training	1990
U.S. Navy	Pensacola, FL

Skills

CompTIA A+ Certified (August 2023)
RHCSA Certified (August 2023)
Software/Operating Systems

- MS Office, Google suite, Libre Office
- Windows, Linux, ChromeOS, iOS, Android
- Oracle VirtualBox, Cisco Packet Tracer
- Microsoft Azure Cloud Services

Programing Languages/Frameworks

 JavaScript, HTML, CSS, NodeJS, Python, Arduino

Electronic Warfare operator

Electrical/Electronic Troubleshooting & Repair Network Management Fundamentals

Cyber Security Fundamentals

Database Management (NoSQL)

Soft Skills

- Problem Solving
- Teamwork/Collaboration
- Dependability
- Critical Thinking
- Verbal/Written Communication
- Organizational Skills

Work Experience

Self Employed, Rideshare Driver	Summer 2014 – Winter 2020
 Vehicle operation & maintenance 	Uber, Lyft
Retail Associate – Supervisor	Spring 2007 – Spring 2014
 Grocery Zone Manager 	Wal-Mart
Truck Driver	Spring 2002 – Winter 2007
 Operation & Routine maintenance over-the-road truck 	Schneider National, J.B. Hunt
U.S Coast Guard Licensed Captain, 500 GT Coastal	Summer 1997 – Fall 2001
 Captain/Engineer Eco-tour Vessels 	Allen Marine Tours, Aramark
Electronic Warfare Technician, E-5	1987 – 1993
Electronics repair & maintenance	U.S. Navy